

Muhammad Moiz Siddique

(+92) 3062890575 | muhammadmoiz0087@gmail.com |

https://www.muhammadmoizsiddigue.com/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-moiz-siddique-74419b166/

Skype: live:muhammadmoiz2000991

Flat no. B-805, Al-minal tower, Block 3A, Gulistan e Johar, 75200, Karachi, Pakistan

About me:

I am a passionate and determined candidate who has transformed his hobby into a career, seeking an opportunity with a reputable organisation. I am an accomplished Associate Software Developer with over 3+ years of experience leading projects by acting as an architect, developer and programmer analyst.

WORK EXPERIENCE

07/06/2022 - CURRENT - Karachi, Pakistan

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - THE DESIGNRY

- I'm working as **team lead** on more than 2+ project, having a **team of 4 peoples**.
- I worked with modern javascript frameworks and libraries such as **Angular**, **React JS**, **Node JS**, **React Native** and also working on **PHP**, **Laravel**, **Codelgniter**, **Python** and **Databases**.
- Worked on the projects with the team to resolve complex issues and to provide a better solution.
- Integrated **third-party tools** and components into applications.
- I have to manage and maintain the daily workflow
- Developed robust, scalable, modular and API-centric infrastructures.
- · Organize a daily **scrum meeting** to identify, prioritize and execute tasks in the software development life cycle
- Manage and update the **CI/CD deployment pipeline**, review and debug code.
- Collaborated with clients to define solution requirements and manage **JIRA** tickets.
- Promoted experience with **Kubernetes**, **Docker** and **Amazon Web Services**.
- Identified and documented project changes with proactive budget oversight.
- Analyzed proposed technical solutions based on customer requirements.
- Tested troubleshooting methods and documented resolutions for inclusion in knowledge base for support team
- Implement modern/best programming techniques and infrastructures such as SOLID principles, SaaS, Procedural Programming, Object-oriented Programming, Functional Programming, etc.

01/06/2019 - 31/05/2022 - Karachi, Pakistan

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER - ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Working on Full Stack Technologies such as **Angular**, **React Js**, **Node JS** and others.
- Improved application designs with addition of new features and infrastructure.
- Integrated Build systems for example **Bable** and **Webpacks**.
- Handle API Integration and Wekhooks
- Optimised test cases to maximize success of manual software testing.
- Created successful test scripts to manage automated feature testing.
- Handle deployments on **Cloud platforms** such as **AWS** and **Github actions** for deployment pipelines.
- Integrate Payment gateways using third party tools such as Stripe API
- Worked with sql and noSql databases such as Mongodb, MySql, Sql server, postgress Sql.
- $\,^\circ\,$ Handle client meetings and manage JIRA tickets.
- Completed various project few are from the scratch and I'm the lead developer having a small team to work on.

01/06/2018 – 31/10/2018 – Karachi, Pakistan

INTERNSHIP - KARACHI PORT TRUST (KPT)

- I worked alongside some of the most skilled programming professionals.
- I learnt (**Dot**) **Net** programming language.
- I was exposed to the **software infrastructure** used in such a **large sized professional company**.
- Thoroughly understand how **data centers** are utilized in such large organizations works.
- This further helped me increase my **team-working creditability** working within a professional IT department and understanding the **workplace dynamic**.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

16/10/2017 – 18/06/2021 – Main Shahrah e Faisal, 22-E, Block-6, PECHS, Karachi, Pakistan **BACHELOR'S OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE –** Mohammad Ali Jinnah University

PROJECTS

SOCIAL CHAMP (DOT) IO - (https://www.socialchamp.io/)

Tech Stack: Angular, Node Js, Mongo db.

Responsibilities: **Design and develop** new modules, maintain and manage existing application including **bug fixes**, analyze requirement and **estimate ETAs**.

THINK EVOLVE SOLVE - (https://thinkevolvesolve.ie/)

Tech Stack: Angular, Node Js, Azure.

Responsibilities: I'm the **team lead** on this project having **2 members team** to Design, develop and manage frontend, backend and **data pipelines** and **cloud architectures** with **efficient processing** and management of large amounts of data, also **develop interfaces / APIs** for data exchange in Node Js.

Bright Development - (https://bright-development.com/);

Tech Stack: React JS, Node Js, Mongo db.

Responsibilities: **Team lead**, manage daily **workflow**, work on client proposed modules and make sure to provide high quality work, write **test for every new module**, manage and maintain **CI/CD pipeline**, **daily scrum** with team members, handle **client meeting**, manage **JIRA** and assigned work to team.

Black Lion App - (In progress)

Tech Stack: React JS, Node Js, Mongo db, Redis, AWS, All Social Media developer APIs, others.

Responsibilities: **Worked from scratch** on this project and i'm the **Team lead**, having a **4 person team** to manage, **esti mate ETAs**, organize a daily **scrum meeting** to identify, prioritize and execute tasks, daily client meeting, understand client stories and assigned work to the team accordingly, manage and maintain **CI/CD pipelines**, using **SaaS** manage to communicate with **cloud services**, review and debug code, manage **Github actions**, update and maintain **story board**, review and merge **pull request** on Github.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND PLATFORMS

JAVASCRIPT / TYPESCRIPT / JAVA / PYTHON / C / C++ / C# / DOT (NET) / GO LANG / PHP / LARAVEL / HTML / CSS / DIANGO / FLASK / TENSERFLOW

WEB AND APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT

ANGULAR / REACT JS / NODE JS / STENCIL JS / NEST JS / REACT NATIVE / AZURE / AWS / GOOGLE CLOUD / OAUTH / CI-CD PIPELINES / DOCKER / KUBERNETES / AI / GIT / JIRA / BITBUCKET / HEROKU

DATABASE SKILLS

MONGO DB / MY SQL / SQL SERVER / POSTGRESS SQL / REDIS / ORACLE

LANGUAGES

Urdu (Native) / English (Fluent) / Turkish (Basics)

HONOURS AND AWARDS

08/06/2022

JavaScript: Core And Advanced Techniques - Udemy: Online Courses

12/08/2020

Speed Programming (Code Jam) - Google

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Interests

Speed Programming competitions / Learning new courses and certifications / Travelling / Poetry / Guitar/Music / Football / Puzzles and games / Streaming